{"name": "65C  2007-6", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. A fruit salad contains pineapples, apples, bananas, and oranges. It contains twice as many bananas as apples, 10 times as many oranges as pineapples, and the same number of apples as oranges. Jeff made this fruit salad using 1 pineapple. How many of each of the other  fruits did he use?", "choices": {"A": "Apples: 10Bananas: 20Oranges: 10", "B": "Apples: 10Bananas: 20Oranges: 1", "C": "Apples: 10Bananas: 2Oranges: 10", "D": "Apples: 10Bananas: 2Oranges: 1", "E": "Apples: 1Bananas: 2Oranges: 1"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to (2x + 5)(x - 3)?", "choices": {"A": "2x\u00b2 + 11x + 15", "B": "2x\u00b2 + 11x - 15  ", "C": "2x\u00b2 - 11x + 15", "D": " 2x\u00b2 + x + 15 ", "E": "2x\u00b2 -  x - 15"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Let function of 2 variables be defined by f(x,y) = xy -(x - y). What is the value of f(9,7) ?", "choices": {"A": "16", "B": "47", "C": "61", "D": "65", "E": "79"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. What is  of 24% of $7,000 ?", "choices": {"A": "$28", "B": "$280", "C": "$1,008", "D": "$2,800", "E": "$10,080"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. If 4x + 4 = 16 + 2x , then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "6", "C": "10", "D": "24", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. The second term of an arithmetic sequence is -11, and the third term is -38. What is the first term?(Note: In an arithmetic sequence, consecutive terms differ by the same amount.)", "choices": {"A": "-27", "B": "", "C": "11", "D": "16", "E": "27"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. A bag contains 64 marbles, all solid colored. Each marble is either red, yellow, or green. A marble is randomly removed from the bag and then returned to the bag. The probability that this marble is red is . The probability that this marble is yellow is . How many green marbles are in the bag ?", "choices": {"A": "40", "B": "32", "C": "24", "D": "16", "E": "8"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. A small bottling company pays for the water it uses. The monthly cost is a fixed charge of $50 plus $4 for each 1,000 units of water used. Last month, the company used 40,000 units of water. What was the total cost of water for this company last month?", "choices": {"A": "$66", "B": "$160", "C": "$210", "D": "$1,600", "E": "$1,650"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. A square has the same perimeter as a regular hexagon (a 6-sided polygon with all sides congruent and all interior angles congruent). If 1 side of the square is 108 centimeters long, how many centimeters long is 1 side of the hexagon?", "choices": {"A": "72", "B": "90", "C": "108", "D": "216", "E": "648"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. Two workers were hired to begin work at the same time. Worker A's contract called for a starting salary of $20,000 with an increase of $800 after each year of employment. Worker B's contract called for a starting salary of $15,200 with an increase of $2,000 after each year of employment. If x represents the number of full years of employment (that is, the number of yearly increases each worker has received), which of the following equations could be solved to determine the number of years until B's yearly salary equals A's yearly salary?", "choices": {"A": "20,000 + 800x = 15,200 + 2,000x ", "B": "20,000 + 2,000x = 15,200 + 800x ", "C": "800x + 2,000x = x", "D": "800x + 2,000x = 20,000 ", "E": "800x + 2,000x = 15,200"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. If I = PRT, then which of the following is an expression for T in terms of I, P, and R ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "IPR", "D": "I - PR", "E": "I + PR"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. The measure of \u2220QOR in the figure below is 140\u00b0. The measure of 3 angles are given in terms of x, measures in degrees. What is the measure of \u2220QOS ?", "choices": {"A": " 96\u00b0", "B": "100\u00b0", "C": "120\u00b0", "D": "138\u00b0", "E": "140\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. A Fahrenheit thermometer outside reads 57\u00b0F. The temperature is 20\u00b0F warmer indoors. What is the indoor temperature, C, in degrees Celsius?(Note: F = C + 32) ", "choices": {"A": "14\u00b0C", "B": "25\u00b0C", "C": "34\u00b0C", "D": "77\u00b0C", "E": "81\u2103"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. If a - b = 5 and c = 7a - 9 - 7b, then c = ?", "choices": {"A": "-4", "B": "-2", "C": "26", "D": "35", "E": "44"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Dena ran  miles on Monday and  miles on Tuesday. The total distance, in miles, Dena ran during those 2 days is within which of the following ranges ?", "choices": {"A": "At least  and less than ", "B": "At least  and less than 6 ", "C": "At least 6 and less than ", "D": "At least  and less than ", "E": "At least  and less than "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. A boat leaves a dock and sails directly north for 5 miles. It then turns and sails 12 miles east. How many miles is the boat from the dock?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "11", "C": "12", "D": "13", "E": "17"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. A mathematical processor in a computer can add a number to a running total in 0.000 000 045 seconds. This processor can add 10,000,000,000 numbers to the running total in how many seconds?", "choices": {"A": "0.0045 ", "B": "0.45 ", "C": "4.5 ", "D": "45 ", "E": "450"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. Tira's dog's rectangular pen is 10 feet wide by 25 feet long. Tira wants to increase the area by 200 square feet by increasing the width and length by the same amount. What will be the new dimensions (width by length), in feet?", "choices": {"A": "15 by 30", "B": "18 by 25 ", "C": "20 by 45 ", "D": "30 by 35 ", "E": "50 by 65"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. The lengths of the sides of a triangle are 3 consecutive odd integers. If the perimeter of the triangle is 33 inches, what is the length, in inches, of the longest side?", "choices": {"A": "7", "B": "9", "C": "11", "D": "13", "E": "15"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of the line with equation 2y - 6x = 4 ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "4", "D": "6", "E": "-3"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. In the figure below, points K, Q, P, and N are collinear, and distances marked are in meters. The area of rectangle KLMN is 33 square meters. What is the area of trapezoid LQPM, in square meters?", "choices": {"A": "18", "B": "21", "C": "24", "D": "27", "E": "48"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. Use the following information to answer questions 22-24.Quadrilateral ABCD is shown below in the standard(x,y) coordinate plane. For this quadrilateral, AB = 5, BC = 3, CD = , and DA = 6, all in coordinate units.22. Which of the following is closest to the perimeter of quadrilateral ABCD, in coordinate units?", "choices": {"A": "14.0", "B": "15.0", "C": "19.8", "D": "22.5", "E": "26.0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Use the following information to answer questions 22-24.Quadrilateral ABCD is shown below in the standard(x,y) coordinate plane. For this quadrilateral, AB = 5, BC = 3, CD = , and DA = 6, all in coordinate units.23. What is the length of AC in coordinate units?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "8", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. Use the following information to answer questions 22-24.Quadrilateral ABCD is shown below in the standard(x,y) coordinate plane. For this quadrilateral, AB = 5, BC = 3, CD = , and DA = 6, all in coordinate units.24. Which of the following are the coordinates of the image of D under a 90\u00b0 counterclockwise rotation about the origin?", "choices": {"A": "(-5,-1) ", "B": "(-1,-5) ", "C": "(1,-5)", "D": "(1,5)", "E": "(5,-1)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. Which of the following letters of the alphabet has at least 1 reflectional symmetry and at least 1 rotational symmetry?(Note: The angle of rotation for the rotational symmetry must be less than 360\u00b0.)", "choices": {"A": "H", "B": "M", "C": "N", "D": "S", "E": "T"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. What is the coefficient of x9 in the product of the 2 polynomials below?(x5 - 2x4 + 8x3 + 3x\u00b2 + x)(3x4 + x3 - 2x2 + 4) ", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "3", "D": "8", "E": "9"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. Use the following information to answer questions 27-28.The stem-and-leaf plot below shows the number of rebounds a basketball player with the Connecticut Suns grabbed in each of 17 games.(Note: For example, 13 rebounds would have a stem value of 1 and a leaf value of 3.)27. Which of the following is closest to the mean number of rebounds this player grabbed per game? ", "choices": {"A": "7.5", "B": "15.0 ", "C": "15.4 ", "D": "16.0 ", "E": "16.5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Use the following information to answer questions 27-28.The stem-and-leaf plot below shows the number of rebounds a basketball player with the Connecticut Suns grabbed in each of 17 games.(Note: For example, 13 rebounds would have a stem value of 1 and a leaf value of 3.)28. If a game represented in the stem-and-leaf plot is selected randomly, what is the probability that the basketball player grabbed exactly 15 rebounds in that game?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. What is the least common multiple of 3, 5x, 4y, and 6xy?", "choices": {"A": "30xy ", "B": "60xy ", "C": "60x\u00b2y ", "D": "120xy ", "E": "120x\u00b2y"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. The number of clients Galaxy Internet Company acquired in each calendar year can be modeled by the function C(t) = 750r + 320, where t = 0 corresponds to the 1999 calendar year. Using this model, how many clients would you expect Galaxy to acquire in the calendar year 2006 ?", "choices": {"A": "2,990 ", "B": "4,070 ", "C": "4,820 ", "D": "5,570 ", "E": "6,320"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. A line in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane contains the points A(-2,3) and B(10,9). What is the midpoint of AB ?", "choices": {"A": "(4,6)", "B": " (6,3)", "C": "(6,6)", "D": "(8,12)", "E": "(12,6)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. For x2 \u2260 81,  = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Issa bought 2 cases of 12-ounce cans of soda. Each case contained 24 cans. Issa could have bought the same amount of soda by buying how many 16-ounce bottles of soda?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "18", "C": "32", "D": "36", "E": "48"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. When  = 3, r2 - 9s2 = ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "8", "C": "9", "D": "-8", "E": "-9"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. An 8-foot-square sheet of tin from which 4 identical circles are cut is shown below. Each circle is tangent to 2 other circles and tangent to 2 of the edges of the square. What is the approximate area, in square feet, of the remaining tin, as indicated by the shaded region below?", "choices": {"A": "51.4 ", "B": "38.9 ", "C": "19.4 ", "D": "13.7 ", "E": "6.9"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Which of the following lists gives the 3 largest prime numbers that are less than 60 ?", "choices": {"A": "2, 3, and 5", "B": "3, 5, and 7", "C": "37, 47, and 59", "D": "47, 51, and 57", "E": "47, 53, and 59"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. The costs of taxi rides of different lengths, given in quarter miles, are shown in the table below.Each cost consists of a fixed charge and a charge per quarter mile. What is the fixed charge?", "choices": {"A": "$0.40", "B": "$1.00", "C": "$1.50", "D": "$3.75", "E": "$6.50"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. At a time when the sun's rays are striking the level ground at an angle of 37\u00b0, a tree casts a shadow that is 41 feet long, as shown in the figure below. To the nearest foot, how many feet tall is the tree?(Note: sin 37\u00b0\u2248 0.60, cos 37\u00b0\u2248 0.80, tan37\u00b0 \u2248 0.75) ", "choices": {"A": "25", "B": "31", "C": "33", "D": "50", "E": "55"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. A circle in the standard(x,y) coordinate plane has center (11,-9) and radius 8 coordinate units. Which of the following is an equation of the circle?", "choices": {"A": "(x - 11)\u00b2 + (y + 9)\u00b2 = 8", "B": " (x + 11)\u00b2 + (y - 9)\u00b2 = 8", "C": "(x + 11)\u00b2 - (y - 9)\u00b2 = 8", "D": "(x + 11)\u00b2 - (y - 9)\u00b2 = 64", "E": "(x - 11)\u00b2 + (y + 9)\u00b2 = 64"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. What is the largest integer value of n that satisfies the inequality \\frac{n}{12}\" style=\"font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, &quot;PingFang SC&quot;, &quot;Helvetica Neue&quot;, STHeiti, &quot;Microsoft Yahei&quot;, Tahoma, Simsun, sans-serif;\">?", "choices": {"A": "7", "B": "8", "C": "9", "D": "10", "E": "11"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Given f(x) = x\u00b2 + x + 2, what is f(x + h)?", "choices": {"A": "x\u00b2 + x + h + 2 ", "B": "x\u00b2 + h\u00b2 + x + h + 2 ", "C": "x\u00b2 + h\u00b2 + x + h + 4", "D": "(x + h)\u00b2 + x + h + 2 ", "E": "(x + h)\u00b2 + x + 2h + 2"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. In the figure below, E is on AD and C is on BD. The dimensions given are in meters. What is the length, in meters, of CD ?", "choices": {"A": "2,640", "B": "2,784", "C": "3,960", "D": "4,400", "E": "5,840"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. In Lewis Carroll's Alice in Wonderland, Alice drinks from a small bottle and shrinks to a height of 10 inches. Later, Alice eats a cake and quickly grows to a height of over 9 feet. Assume that Alice's height, h inches, t seconds after she finished eating the cake is given by h = 10 + 6t. To the nearest second, how many seconds after Alice finished eating the cake was she 8 feet tall?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "5", "C": "14", "D": "16", "E": "58"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. In \u25b3XYZ, XY \u224c XZ and the measure of \u2220Y is 34\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220X?", "choices": {"A": "34\u00b0", "B": "56\u00b0", "C": "68\u00b0", "D": "73\u00b0", "E": "112\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. A Little League baseball player has batted 120 times and has 25 hits. Starting now, if she gets a hit each time she is at bat, what is the least number of times she must be at bat to raise her batting average to at least  300?(Note: batting average=  ) ", "choices": {"A": "11", "B": "16", "C": "36", "D": "61", "E": "161"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Suppose 0 &lt; a &lt; 1. Which of the following has the greatest value?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "a2", "D": "a3", "E": "log a "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. Casey and 3 friends are snow sledding on a 4-person toboggan like the one shown in the figure below. Each time all 4 of them go down the hill on the toboggan, they sit in a different order, from front to back. What is the maximum number of times they can go down the hill without sitting in the same order twice?", "choices": {"A": "256", "B": "64", "C": "24", "D": "16", "E": "10"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. In the circle below, O is the center. Chord AB is 12 inches long and is 8 inches from O. What is the area, in square inches, of the circle?", "choices": {"A": "36\u03c0", "B": "64\u03c0", "C": "80\u03c0", "D": "100\u03c0", "E": "208\u03c0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. What is the x-intercept of the line that contains the points (-3,5) and (5,1) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "(, 0 )", "B": "(0, )", "C": "(0, 7)", "D": "(7, 0)", "E": "(7, )"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. The graph of one of the following equations is the parabola shown in the standard(x,y) coordinate plane below. Which one? ", "choices": {"A": "y - 3 = (x - 4)2", "B": "y - 3 = 2(x + 4)2", "C": "y - 3 = 2(x - 4)2", "D": "y - 3 = (x + 4)2", "E": "y + 3 = (x - 4)2"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Suppose 0\u00b0 &lt; x &lt; 90\u00b0 and tan x = . What is the value of cos x + sin x ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. In the figure below, AB = BC ,and AC is a diameter of the circle, having a length of 4 centimeters. What is the area of \u25b3ABC, in square centimeters?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "4", "C": "8", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. In \u25b3ABC, shown below, angle measures are as marked and the length given is in meters. Which of the following is an expression for the length, in meters, of AB?(Note: The law of sines states that for a triangle with sides of lengths a, b, and c opposite angles of measure \u03b1, \u03b2, and \u03b3, respectively, . ) ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. The length of arc  of a circle is equal to  of the circumference of the circle. The length of the arc is 4\u03c0 inches. What is the radius, in inches, of the circle?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "5", "C": "8", "D": "10", "E": "20"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55.   = ? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. A function is defined by g(x) = -x3. Which of the following is an expression for g(g(x)?", "choices": {"A": "-x9", "B": "-x3", "C": "x3", "D": "x6", "E": "x9"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. The function values for h(x) vary directly as x for all real numbers. The graph of y = h(x) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane is:", "choices": {"A": "a line with a y-intercept at 0.", "B": "a line with a y-intercept, but not at 0.", "C": "a line with no y-intercept.", "D": "a hyperbola.", "E": "neither a Iine nor a hyperbola."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. A data set of integers has 5 members. The median of the data set is 6. The only mode of the data set is 2. The mean of the data set is 5. Which of the following statements must be true about the data set?", "choices": {"A": "The sum of the 5 integers is 30.", "B": "The sum of the 5 integers is 10.", "C": "The median of the 3 largest integers is 6.", "D": "The largest integer is 9.", "E": "The largest integer is 8."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. A rectangular box is to be made from a rectangular piece of sheet metal 20 inches wide and 30 inches long by cutting a square piece of equal size from each of the corners and bending up the sides so that they make a 90\u00b0 angle with the base. The base of the finished box will be 200 square inches. About how many inches high will the box be?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "10", "C": "15", "D": "20", "E": "30"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. Which of the following expressions gives the area, in square inches, of \u25b3FGH, shown below with the given side lengths in inches?", "choices": {"A": "30 cos 65\u00b0", "B": "30 sin 65\u00b0", "C": "15 cos 65\u00b0", "D": "15 sin 65\u00b0", "E": "15 tan 65\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}]}